A Guide to the Papers of Kenneth Brown, ca. 1880-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Kenneth Brown ca. 1880-1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9732
Ca. 3000 items (9 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection is from the estate of Francesca Boone, and was purchased from the H. & W. Auction Company, of Troy, Virginia, in July of 1971.
Biographical/Historical Information
The son of Franklin B. and Caroline Morrill Brown, Kenneth Brown (1868- ) was born in Chicago and lived in Europe as a youth. A University of Virginia alumnus and Harvard graduate, he worked on several newspapers including the Boston Journal and the New York Commercial Advertiser. In 1904 he married Demetra Vaka (1877-1946), a Byzantine Greek who had come to the United States at the age of 17. Together they went to Greece during World War I, interviewed King Constantine, Eleutherios Venizelos, and other leaders, and wrote about their observations. In 1921 the couple did a series of articles on Turkey. Mrs. Brown is known also for several novels and works of non-fiction, including Haremlik (1909), In the Shadow of Islam (1911), and In the Grasp of the Sultan (1916).
Scope and Content
The Papers of Kenneth Brown contain ca. 3,000 items, ca. 1880-1954, chiefly photographs of the Brown family, of Turkey, Greece, and various western European countries, and of Greek and Turkish leaders of the World War I era. There is some correspondence of the Browns (1876-1954), some bills to Francesca Boone, Kenneth Brown's sister, three photograph albums, and seven scrapbooks, chiefly filled with clippings, belonging to Kenneth Brown, Caroline Brown, and Francesca Boone. There are also a number of handwritten newspapers that the young Kenneth Brown wrote in Europe.
Contents List
- Letters and postcards to and from Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Brown 1900-1919 (Box 1)
- Woodrow Wilson to Mrs. Kenneth Brown 1918 February 7, TLS w/envelope (Box 1)
- Secretary to Woodrow Wilson to Mrs. Kenneth Brown 1918 March 11, TLS (Box 1)
- Letters and postcards to Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Brown 1920-1929 (Box 1)
- Letters and postcards, chiefly from Kenneth Brown 1930-1939 (Box 1)
- Letters and postcards, chiefly from Kenneth Brown 1940-1954 (Box 1)
- Letters and postcards to and from Kenneth Brown n.d. (Box 1)
- Carbons of publicity for Demetra Vaka (Mrs. Kenneth Brown) n.d. (Box 1)
- Clippings, re: Demetra Vaka (Mrs. Kenneth Brown) 1918-1932 (Box 1)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, A-B 1914-1928 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, C 1916-1926 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, D 1914-1926 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, E 1914-1921 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, F 1915-1926 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, G 1914-1926 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, H 1914-1929 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, I 1916-1921 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, J-K 1915-1927 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, L-M 1914-1925 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, N-O 1915-1923 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, P-R 1914-1929 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, S 1915-1925 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, T 1915-1927 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, U-V 1916-1924 (Box 2)
- Bills of Francesca Boone, W-Z 1915-1929 (Box 2)
- Photographs of Demetra Vaka (Mrs. Kenneth Brown) at various ages n.d. (Box 2)
- Photographs and negatives of Demetra Vaka (Mrs. Kenneth Brown) at various ages n.d. (Box 3)
- Photographs of Demetra Vaka ca. 1920 (Box 3)
- Photographs of Kenneth Brown at various ages n.d. (Box 3)
- Photographs of Kenneth Brown as a child ca. 1880 (Box 3)
- Photographs of Edmund Clarence Stedman, signed by Laura Stedman ca. 1908 (Box 3)
- Photographs of a group of Harvard athletes ca. 1890 (Box 3)
- Photographs of Greek Royal family ca. 1920 (Box 3)
- Photographs of Eleutherios Venizelos, his family, and his houses ca. 1920 (Box 3)
- Negatives of photographs of the Venizelos family ca. 1920 (Box 3)
- Photographs and negatives of Greek leaders ca. 1920 (Box 3)
- Photographs and negatives of Turkish leaders ca. 1920 (Box 3)
- Photographs and negatives of various identified people ca. 1920 (Box 4)
- Photographs of unidentified people n.d. (Box 4)
- Photographs of Brown-Boone house ca. 1901 (Box 4)
- Photographs of Kenneth Brown house [in New Hampshire] n.d. (Box 4)
- Photographs and negatives of Virginia scenes ca. 1920 (Box 4)
- Photographs and negatives of Greece 1917-ca. 1930 (Box 4)
- Photographs of Greece 1917-ca. 1930 (Box 4)
- Photographs of Turkey ca. 1920 (Box 5)
- Photographs of Turkey ca. 1920 (Box 5)
- Negatives of Turkey ca. 1920 (Box 5)
- Lists of kinds of photographs n.d. (Box 5)
- Photographs of Italy n.d. (Box 5)
- Photographs of Germany n.d. (Box 6)
- Photographs of Switzerland n.d. (Box 6)
- Photographs of France n.d. (Box 6)
- Photographs of European countries ca. 1920 (Box 6)
- Negatives of photographs of European countries 1910-ca. 1920 (Box 6)
- Photographs of unidentified places n.d. (Box 6)
- "A Little Bit of Love" n.d., TMs (Box 6)
- "The Gray Forsythia Twig" n.d., AMs (Box 6)
- Visas of Mr. and Mrs. Kenneth Brown 1917 (Box 6)
- Printed and typewritten material, re: Demetra Vaka, Greece 1936-? (Box 6)
- Religious pamphlets 1930-1939 (Box 6)
- Pamphlets about Greece 1913-1926 (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous pamphlets 1910-1936 (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous printed material 1911-1949 (Box Box 7)
- Miscellaneous articles n.d. (Box 7)
- Photograph album, with photographs of Kenneth Brown's [New Hampshire] home n.d. (Box 8)
- Photograph album with pictures, chiefly of Paris n.d. (Box 8)
- Scrapbook of clippings of articles of Kenneth Brown, in the Harvard Advocate, the Boston Journal, and the Magpie 1889-1896 (Box 9)
- Photograph album of Kenneth Brown's house and family 1891-? (Box 9)
- Photograph of Harvard Class of 1891 1916 (Box 9)
- Photograph of Harvard Class of 1891 with families 1916 June 20 (Box 9)